Preliminary Inventory to the Benjamin Shannon Allen Papers, 1910-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Benjamin Shannon Allen Papers,
1910-1967
54001
Allen, Benjamin Shannon, 1883-1963
3 manuscript boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 2 oversize boxes, 2 envelopes (3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, press releases, clippings, other printed matter, and photographs, relating to activities of the Commission for Relief in Belgium, U.S. Food Administration and U.S. Fuel Administration during World War I, and of the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies and Finnish Relief Fund during World War II, to political conditions in the U.S., and to Herbert Hoover.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); Finnish Relief Fund; National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies; United States. Food Administration; United States. Fuel Administration; International relief; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief; Belgium; Finland; United States--Politics and government; United States--Foreign relations; United States--Politics and government--20th century; Journalists
Container List
- Correspondence with Herbert Hoover, Lou Henry Hoover, and other Hoovers
  - 1910-1919. Includes letter to President Wilson (Box 1., Folder 1.)
  - 1920-1929 (Folder 2.)
  - 1930-1939 (Folder 3.)
  - 1940-1949 (Folder 4.)
  - 1950-1967 (Folder 5.)
  - Food for Small Democracies. Mostly printed or mimeographed material (Folder 6.)
  - Hoover Institution - Dedication, 1941 (Folder 7.)
  - Comité National de Secours et d'Alimentation, 1914-1918,Séance solennelle du 5 juillet 1958 pour recevoir M. Herbert Hoover, Brussels, 1958 (illustrated)
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous (mostly political)
  - 1910-1919. Includes C.R.B. and United States. Food Administration material (Box 2., Folder 1.)
  - 1920-1929 (Folder 2.)
  - 1930-1939 (Folder 3.)
  - 1940-1949 (Folder 4.)
  - 1950-. Includes Herbert Hoover Foundation, and Herbert Hoover Birthplace Foundation material (Folder 5.)
  - Correspondence - Frank Feltzer, 1939-1940 (Folder 6.)
- Books (Box 3.)
  - Myrop, Kr.,The Imprisonment of the Ghent Professors, (Holder and Stoughton, 1917)
  - Foundation for American Resource Management sponsored annotated bibliography,California Coast Redwood,(1957, San Francisco)
  - Chapter from unidentified publication entitled "The Famine in Irish Oral Tradition" autographed on front by Roger McHugh to Ben and Vicki
  - Pamphlet by Haven A. Mason,A World Hegemony To Secure Peace on Earth and Promote Good Will Toward Men(Ben S. Allen wrote bibliography of author on back inside cover)
  - Printed or mimeographed material. Includes some Herbert Hoover and relief administrations material
- Clippings on the Finnish Relief Fund, 1939-1945 (Box 4.)
- One postcard (Box 5.)
- Photographs of the complete set of United States. Food Administration posters
- Photographs of Herbert Hoover (a few rare snapshots included); photographs of United States. Food Administration members, friends, and posters
- Scrapbook of photographs of members of C.R.B., etc.
- Flour sack (Folder 6.)
- Photographs
  - 3 prints of Herbert Hoover, 1938; 6 prints of Herbert Hoover; 1 print of Ray Lyman Wilbur; 3 prints of Gunnison, Colorado, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover, Benjamin Allen and others, Colorado 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover, Colfax, California, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover, Benjamin Allen and others, 1938; 1 print of John Hallowell; 1 print of Edward Chambers; 1 print of Lou D. Sweet; 1 print of Raymond Pearl; 1 print of Theodore Whitmarsh; 1 print of Julius Barnes; 1 print of George Rolph; 2 prints of Herbert Hoover and others, Grass Valley, California, 1935; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and Charles Hebberd, Spokane, Washington, 1938; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and Otto Swangson; 1 print Herbert Hoover and others; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and others, San Francisco World's Fair, 1939; 3 prints of Herbert Hoover and others, Eugene, Oregon, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and unidentified man; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and Mrs. George B. Simmons; 2 prints of Herbert Hoover and others, Cebolla, California, 1939; 1 print of Herbert Hoover and others; 1 print of Judge Lindsay; 1 print of Tom Ellis; 1 print of the Conference of United States Food Administration; 1 unidentified print (Folder A)
  - 11 photographs of United States Food Administration posters (Folder B)
  - 1 album of prints of Herbert Hoover, U.S. Food Administration officials, food conservation photographs, and photographs of U.S. Food Administration posters, 1917-1919 (Folder fC)
  - 1 album of photographs of U.S. Food Administration posters and press releases, 1917-1919. (Folder fD)